(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
うわー！
Wow!
はい、開口一番歌ったのかーみたいな感じで
Yes, so it felt like I sang right away, but...
行くかと思いきや、始まったばかりです！
...believe it or not, it's just getting started!
みんな盛り上がってるかー？
Is everyone excited?!
始まったばかりです。えっと...
It's just started. Um...
あの、ハッシュタグ「ノエル生誕はっぴーLIVE」で
With the hashtag #NoelBirthdayHappyLive,
今日は1時間いっぱい呟いてください！
please tweet a lot for an hour today!
今回はね、なんと！久しぶりなバラエティパートもあります！
This time, believe it or not! There's also a variety segment for the first time in a while!
バラエティパートとその後にライブパートがあるので
Since there's a variety segment followed by a live segment,
ぜひぜひ盛り上がってください！
please, please get excited!
じゃあちょっとね、団長バラエティパートの準備があるんで
Well then, Dancho has some preparations for the variety segment,
早速準備していきたいと思います！
so I'm going to get ready right away!
いっぱいスクショ撮ったりね、あの感想とかいっぱい呟いてね！
Take lots of screenshots and tweet lots of your thoughts!
ということで準備してきます！
So, I'm going to get ready!
おまーーーー！
OMA----!
真の牛丼女王は誰だ！
Who is the true Beef Bowl Queen?!
第1回ホロライブ牛丼女王決定戦！
The 1st Hololive Beef Bowl Queen Contest!
フーー！
Woo!
イェーイ！
Yay!
第1回 牛丼女王決定戦
1st Beef Bowl Queen Contest
はい、ということで、まずはこの大会の絶対王者を公表しましょう！
Yes, so first, let's introduce the absolute champion of this competition!
牛丼を愛して300年
Loving beef bowl for 300 years
朝はおろしポン酢牛丼
Grated radish with ponzu beef bowl in the morning
昼はチーズ牛丼
Cheese beef bowl for lunch
夜は通常牛丼
Normal beef bowl at night
1日3食、牛丼もどんとこい！
Three meals a day, bring on the beef bowls!
「ホロライブ一 牛丼を愛している！」と豪語する
Boasting that "I love beef bowl more than anyone in Hololive!"
白銀ノエル様！
Shirogane Noel-sama!
イェーーイ！白銀ノエルです！
Yay! I'm Shirogane Noel!
いや、牛丼好きって言ったら団長っしょ！ということで
Well, when you think of beef bowl lovers, you think of Dancho! So,
絶対に負けません！
I definitely won't lose!
今日は楽しく食べて帰ります！
Today I'll eat and have fun before going home!
そして、挑戦者はこの方！
And the challenger is this person!
最近牛丼を食べたのは半年前
The last time she ate beef bowl was six months ago
今日は団長から牛丼の真髄を学びに来た！
Today she came to learn the essence of beef bowl from Dancho!
肉より野菜派！風真いろは殿！
Vegetable over meat person! Kazama Iroha-dono!
イェーーイ！お肉食べるの久しぶりでござる！
Yay! It's been a long time since I ate meat!
あ、今日の朝ご飯はキュウリをかじってきました！
Ah, I gnawed on a cucumber for breakfast today!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look after me!
はい、そしてね、司会進行はこの私、レシピ本を出させていただいております
Yes, and for the MC, I, who have published a recipe book,
癒月ちょこが務めさせていただきます！
Yuzuki Choco, will be serving!
イェーーイ！
Yay!
この大会では...
In this competition...
...一般的な牛丼
...a general beef bowl,
...1000円超えの高級牛丼
...an expensive beef bowl over 1000 yen,
ちょこの愛情たっぷり手作り牛丼の3種類をご用意させていただいております！
and Choco's handmade beef bowl full of love, we have 3 types prepared!
やったー！
Hooray!
一般的な牛丼
General Beef Bowl
高級牛丼
Premium Beef Bowl
手作り牛丼
Handmade Beef Bowl
まずはね、見た目を確認していただきつつ、そのあとはね、実食して
First, while having you check the appearance, after that, you'll eat them and
それぞれを当てていただくという、とてもシンプルな、かつ簡単な勝負となっております
guess each one, it's a very simple and easy contest
早速始めていきましょう！
Let's get started right away!
はい！
Yes!
はい、ということで、お二人の目の前に3種類の牛丼が用意されました！
Yes, so 3 types of beef bowls have been prepared in front of you two!
うわー！牛丼だ、牛丼だー！
Wow! It's beef bowl, beef bowl!
まずはね、右側の牛丼はいかがでしょうか？
First, how about the beef bowl on the right?
いや、これはなんかいつものお馴染みな感じがしますよ
Well, this feels like the familiar usual one
もう見た目からしてね
just from the look of it
匂いも、なんかいつも馴染んでいる牛丼な気がしますね
The smell too, it feels like the beef bowl I'm always familiar with
いろは様も分かります？
Do you know too, Iroha-sama?
見た目チェック中...
Checking the appearance...
牛丼女王決定戦
Gyudon Queen Decision Battle
見た目チェック中…
Visual check in progress...
いざ、の...
Alright, so...
牛丼を見るのが本当に久しぶりすぎて
It's really been a long time since I looked at beef bowls like this.
あの、全部確かに違うけど
Well, they definitely all look different, but...
どれがいつも見たことある牛丼？って今なってるでござるな
I'm wondering which one is the beef bowl I usually see.
なるほどなるほど。そしたら真ん中の方の牛丼はいかがでしょう？
I see, I see. Then, how about the beef bowl in the middle?
真ん中の。えっとこちらはあれなんですよ
The middle one? Well, this one is...
玉ねぎが細かいですね
The onions are cut quite small.
そう、牛丼って結構玉ねぎがね、ちょっと大きめに切られてること多いんですけど、これはちょっと細かいということで
Yeah, usually with beef bowls the onions are cut a bit larger, but these are small.
そして肉が多い。つまり...
And there's a lot of meat. In other words...
あ、あ、わかりました、これは
Ah, I see. This must be...
なるほどね、お肉を売りにしてる、その分値段もみたいな感じなのかな
I see, it's the type where they focus on meat quality, and the price reflects that.
なるほどなるほど。しかもちょこ玉ねぎ嫌いなんで
I see. Also, Choco hates onions.
あー、玉ねぎ嫌いなのかもしれないね。これ、玉ねぎないもん、ほとんど
Ah, maybe they really do hate onions. This one has almost none.
はいはいはい、なるほど。そしたらね、一番左側の方の牛丼いかがでしょう？
I see. In that case, how about the beef bowl on the far left?
左側。あー、え、これ玉ねぎいっぱいある！
The left one? Oh, this one has lots of onions!
いっぱい入ってる！
There's so much in here!
さっきのチョコ先生の理論から言うと、じゃあこっちが高級...
Based on Choco-sensei's theory earlier, then this one is high-end...
わかるでござる。匂い嗅いでもいいすか？
I get it. Can I smell it too?
確かに匂い嗅ぎたい
I definitely want to smell it too.
いい匂い。あー、お腹空いてきた
It smells good. Ah, I'm getting hungry.
ちょっと待って、チョコ先生の匂いも嗅いでもいいよ？
Wait a minute, you can smell Choco-sensei too, you know?
あ、チョコ先生の匂いも嗅いだ。ちょっと団長...
Ah, I smelled Choco-sensei too. Wait, Danchou...
あ、ちなみにちょっと手前にあるんで、ちょっと一杯いいすか？
Ah, by the way, there's a drink right here, can I have a sip?
おいおいおい、飲むんじゃないよ！これから実食って言われてるでござるよ！
Hey, hey, hey! Don't drink! We're about to start the tasting!
このジョッキめちゃめちゃオシャレ。なんか見覚えがある人もいると思うんだけど
This mug is so stylish. I think some of you might recognize it...
これ団長がディアンドル衣装でよく飲んでるジョッキなんですけど
This is the mug Danchou often uses when she's in her dirndl outfit.
いいすか？一杯いっちゃって
Is it okay? If I just take one gulp?
プハッ！美味い！
*Gulp* Pwah! Delicious!
うわああああ！
Uwaaaa!
味わかる前に飲んじゃって大丈夫ですか？ノエル様
Are you okay drinking before you've even tasted the food, Noel-sama?
全然全然。むしろ景気づけの一杯だから全然
I'm fine, totally fine! It's just a drink to liven things up!
余裕っすよ。任せて
I've got this. Leave it to me!
それではね、実食なんですが
Alright then, time for the tasting...
ちょっとね、目隠しをして食べていただこうと思います
I'm going to have you both wear blindfolds while you eat.
なるほど。それで見ためじゃわかんない、本当口でね
I see. So we can't tell by looks, only by taste.
はい。よいしょ。お、それでは、どうぞ
Yes. There we go. Alright then, go ahead.
じゃあちょっと団長、あー、何も見えん、何も見えん
Alright, Danchou's going in... Ah, I can't see anything at all!
本当。本当。はい、じゃあ。いろは様も
Truly. Truly. Alright, now Iroha-sama too.
はい、本当何も見えない。はい、では前の方に
Yes, I really can't see a thing. Okay, step forward.
はい。かわいい。ちょっとどこだ
Yes. So cute! Wait, where is it?
実食中
Tasting in progress
それではね、一つ目の方食べさせいただきましょう。いただきます！
Alright, let's have you try the first one. Let's eat!
あらあらノエル様、そんな大きな口を開けて
Oh my, Noel-sama, opening your mouth so wide!
美味いですね。ちょっと団長、牛丼食べる時にいつもかけてるマストアイテムがありまして
This is good! By the way, I have a must-have item that I always use when I eat beef bowls.
あら、何かしら？
Oh, what would that be?
柚子七味なんですけど、ただ目隠ししてるから、ちょっと撒き散らしそう
It's Yuzu Shichimi, but since I'm blindfolded, I might scatter it everywhere.
えっと、あ、穴が...
Wait, the shaker hole is...
ちょっと待ってくださいね。チョコが開けてあげるわ、穴ぐらい
Hold on a second. Choco will open the hole for you.
よし、はい。おー、見えないとこで手が動かされている
There we go. Oh, someone's hands are moving where I can't see!
かかってる？かかってるかな？はい。めっちゃいっぱいかかったわね
Is it on? I wonder if it's on... Wow, a lot went on there!
違う罰ゲームみたいになってきた。じゃあ、ちょっといただきます
This is starting to feel like a punishment game. Well, I'll take a bite.
あ、やばい柚子七味の匂いが爽やか
Ah, the refreshing scent of Yuzu Shichimi is amazing!
あらあらあら。いろは様はどう？
Oh my, oh my. How about you, Iroha-sama?
んー、美味しい！
Mmm, delicious!
お味はどんな感じ？甘い？しょっぱい？
How's the flavor? Sweet? Salty?
え、なんだろう。でも、しょっぱくはない、甘だれみたいな味がするでござる
Hmm, let's see. It's not salty, it tastes like a sweet sauce.
おー。団長もさっきまで甘くて美味しかったんですけど、すごい辛いです
Oh, it was sweet and tasty for me too a second ago, but now it's super spicy!
今、ありえないほどかけたもんね
Well, you did put an unbelievable amount on just now.
え、めっちゃ美味しい。お肉ってこんなに美味しかったんでござるな
Wow, this is so good. I didn't know meat could be this delicious!
はい。それではね、次の牛丼に移っていきましょうか
Alright. Now then, let's move on to the next beef bowl.
はい、それではお二方とも、二杯目よろしくお願いします
Okay, both of you, please try the second one.
はい。じゃあどちらかと言うとさっぱり...
Yes. If anything, this one is more refreshing...
さっぱり系？
A refreshing type?
あらあら、そんな大きな口で、かき込んで。お肉いっぱいね
Oh my, stuffing your mouth so wide! There's plenty of meat.
柔らかい？
Is it soft?
え、あ、でも待って、玉ねぎ入ってる、こっち
Wait, oh, hold on, this one has onions in it.
玉ねぎ、玉ねぎあるかないかさっき近くでわからなかった...あ、本当だ
Onions... I couldn't tell if there were onions when I looked closely... Oh, you're right.
へ？
Eh?
ちなみにね 今持ってる 風真様のね あのスプーン
By the way, that spoon Kazama-sama is holding...
お肉が１つも乗っておりません！
Doesn't have a single piece of meat on it!
ちょっと待って！
Wait a minute!
あれ？見えないでござる！
Wait, I can't see!
嘘 これご飯？
No way, is this just rice?
しょうがないわね ちょっと貸しなさい
Oh, fine then. Here, let me help.
あ ありがとうございます え これご飯？
T-Thank you. Wait, is this just rice?
うん ご飯だけ
Yeah, just rice.
あれ？ ご飯だけなのよ 風真殿
Wait, it's just rice, Kazama-dono.
やはり やはり肉は避けていくのか 風真のことを
Is the meat... is the meat avoiding me after all?
おかしいわね はい あーん
That's strange. Here, say 'ah'.
え？ お口開けて？ はい あーん
Eh? Open your mouth. Come on, 'ah'.
美味しい？
Is it good?
うんうん
Mm-hmm.
牛丼はうめえよな 何だろう
Gyudon really is the best. What is this...?
めっちゃ嗅いでる
She's smelling it a lot.
生姜みたいな匂いする
It smells like ginger.
あ 生姜！ 分かる
Ah, ginger! I get it.
うん 生姜効いてる
Yeah, the ginger's strong.
ノエル様もう半分以上食べてんだけど やばいって
Noel-sama's already eaten more than half! This is bad.
肉の 何だろう
The meat's... how do I put it...?
こうフォースを感じる 肉のフォースを感じるから
I can feel the force. I feel the meat's force.
見なくても食べれる
So I can eat it without looking.
あ 今食べてるのは白米だけですわ
Ah, I'm only eating white rice right now.
強すぎる あーい それではね
You're too much. Alright, then...
そろそろ３杯目の方 試食していきましょう
Let's move on to tasting the third bowl.
３食目 試食スタート！
Third meal tasting, start!
はい いただきます
Alright, let's eat.
良い匂いする
It smells good.
あ 良い匂いする 甘めな匂いがするね
Oh, it does. It has a sweet smell.
うーん！ うーん！
Mmm! Mmm!
おっと 反応が今までとちょっと違うぞ
Whoa, the reaction is a bit different this time.
え 美味い おっと
Eh, it's good! Oh?
どうですか？ ノエル様
How is it, Noel-sama?
美味しい うまい
Delicious. It's good.
何か味が染みてる
The flavor's really soaked in.
うん 染みてる？ うん 染みわたってるわ
Yeah, soaked in? Yeah, it's permeated.
風真殿は？
And Kazama-dono?
美味しい 何か玉ねぎとお肉 ちゃんと両方の味がする
It's good! I can taste both the onion and the meat.
あら 玉ねぎが
Oh, the onions...?
何かね 甘い 甘い！
They're, like, sweet. So sweet!
ええ そうなの？ そうなの？
Eh, is that so? Really?
そう 甘さを感じるな
Yes, I can definitely taste the sweetness.
どう？ どう？ 甘い？
Well? Is it sweet?
甘い 甘いです 今までで一番甘い
Sweet. It's sweet. The sweetest so far.
一番甘い そう 甘さを感じるね めっちゃ美味しい 甘くて
The sweetest? Yeah, it's sweet. It's very delicious and sweet.
甘さを感じます おら 最後何かめちゃめちゃ好評ね
I can taste the sweetness. Wow, this last one is very popular.
あーい そしたらね 皆様 後ろを向いていただいて
Alright, then. Everyone, please turn around.
はい いいですか？ 目隠しの方 お取りください
Okay, are you ready? Please remove your blindfolds.
あ 世界が明るい あ 明るい まぶしい まぶしい
Ah, the world is so bright! It's so bright! Blinding!
え ノエル先輩そんな どうやって食べたの？ すごい 完食できてる
Eh, Noel-senpai, how did you eat that much? Amazing, you finished it!
ご回答のご記入 よろしくお願いします
Please write down your answers.
もう ノエル様はね 簡単でしょう
For Noel-sama, this must be easy.
え 風真殿は？ 書けてるかな よいしょ ピー
What about Kazama-dono? Is she writing? There we go.
あれ？ 風真ちゃん 悩んでるのかな あれあれ？
Wait, is Kazama-chan struggling? Oh?
おっと もうノエル様は余裕だな あらー
Whoa, Noel-sama's already done. Wow.
もう口の中が答え知ってるからね あらー
My mouth already knows the answer. Wow.
それではね 回答見てみましょうか
Well then, let's see the answers.
ノエル様の回答を ドドン！
Noel-sama's answer is... Ta-da!
A 高級牛丼
B 一般的牛丼
C ちょこ先♡♡♡
A: High-end Gyudon
B: Generic Gyudon
C: Choco-seni♡♡♡
はい これです
Yes, here it is.
あーい じゃあちょっと読み上げてもらってもいいですか？
Alright, could you read them out for us?
一番最初に食べた Aが高級牛丼
The first one I ate, A, is the high-end gyudon.
その次が一般的な牛丼で
The next one is the generic gyudon.
最後に食べたのが ちょこ先生♡ チュッチュラだと思います
And the last one I ate is Choco-sensei. I'm sure of it.
あ なるほど これ理由は？
Ah, I see. And the reason?
まず 最初の牛丼なんですけど 味がね 色々な
Well, for the first gyudon, the flavor had various...
特に一般的牛丼は もう何度も食べ続けてて思うんですけど
Especially the generic one, I've eaten it so many times.
あの甘めな牛丼もあるんですよ はいはいはい
You know, there are sweet gyudons too. Yes, yes, yes.
でも 多分今回色味からして 多分一般的な牛丼は
But this time, judging by the color, the generic one...
あ あそこだなと思ったんですよね そう とある所で
I thought, 'Ah, it must be from there.' Yes, from a certain place.
そこは 甘くないんですよ 甘め少なめ
The gyudon there isn't sweet. It's less sweet.
え そこまでリサーチ済み？
Eh, you've researched that much?
いやもう 色味で分かる 色味でちょっと あの濃い茶色とかだと
No, I can tell by the color. If it's a dark brown...
結構味が付けられてるんだけど やっぱね あのちょっと味が何て言うの
It's usually heavily flavored, but you know, the flavor is...
白っぽいというか その それは あのさっぱりとして 何杯でもいけるぞっていう
Sort of pale? It's light, and you feel like you could eat many bowls.
感じの はいはいはい で なった時に
That kind of feeling. Yes, yes. And when that happened...
Aは味が濃かったんですよ
A had a rich flavor.
お なるほど 濃くて お肉が 結構ね 何か
Oh, I see. It was rich, and the meat was... like...
とろける感じ ちょっと脂身とかも はいはいはい
It had a melting texture. The fat too... Yes, yes.
っていう感じがしたんで高級牛丼 でもちょっとここはね まだわかんなかった
That's why I thought it was high-end. But I wasn't 100% sure yet.
色味的に 濃いのが２種類あったから で
Because there were two dark-colored ones. And...
Bが食べた瞬間に あ いつもの！って思いました
The moment I tasted B, I thought, 'Ah, the usual one!'
おお さすが さすが お肉の感じした あの舌触りとか
Oh, as expected! The texture of the meat, the mouthfeel...
うんうん 何かもうスルスル入る感じが もう一般牛丼かなと思って
Yeah, it just went down so smoothly. I thought, 'This must be the generic one.'
で 最後は おお はい
And finally... Oh, yes.
優しい。
It's gentle.
特に一番味が濃かったこれは、多分それくらい愛情込められてるんじゃないかなって。
Especially this one with the strongest flavor, I think it's because that much love was put into it.
おー、なるほど！
Oh, I see!
すごい。あと玉ねぎがすごい何か煮込まれてる感じ。
Amazing. Also the onions feel really stewed.
チョコ先あんまり好きじゃないって言ったけど、
I said Choco-sen doesn't like them much, but...
チョコ先は自分自身の...自分のために料理をするのではなく我々のために料理してくれたから、
Choco-sen didn't cook for herself, but for us...
確かに！
True!
ね、玉ねぎね、野菜を...チョコちゃんとかで。
Yeah, the onions, the vegetables... with Choco-chan.
だから玉ねぎ多めでしかも優しくね、煮込んでみたいな感じで。
So there's lots of onions and it's stewed gently, like that.
確かに。
True.
それでは、いろは様の回答を見ていきましょう！
Well then, let's look at Iroha-sama's answer!
はい、どうぞ！
Here you go!
A. ごうきゅう!! B. いっぱん C. ちょこ先生の！
A. High-end!! B. General C. Choco-sensei's!
実は、一緒なんでござるよ！
Actually, it's the same!
完璧。
Perfect.
でも正直めっちゃ迷った。特にAとCですごく迷って、
But honestly, I was really torn. Especially between A and C.
なるほどね。
I see.
え、このAは、まず美味しい！ってなって、
Uh, this A, first it was "Delicious!"
なんか食べたことない美味しさを感じて。
I felt a deliciousness I'd never tasted before.
なるほどなるほど。
I see, I see.
で、Bはなんか食べてるうちにやっと食べ方ちょっと慣れてきて、
And B, as I was eating, I finally got a bit used to how to eat it...
「あ、これ何か半年後ぐらいに...」
"Ah, this is like in six months..."
食べたことある！
I've eaten it!
そう！なんかこの感じはひょっとして風真、半年後ぐらいに何か経験したことあるかもしれないと思って。
Yes! I thought maybe Kazama had experienced this feeling about six months ago.
で、Cはなんか本当にめっちゃ甘くて美味しかったんでござるよ。
And C was really sweet and delicious.
ってAとCがどっちだろうってすごく迷っちゃって。
So I was really torn between A and C.
なるほどね。
I see.
でも比べた時にずっと食べてたいのはCだから、Cがチョコ先のだなと思って。
But when I compared them, the one I wanted to keep eating was C, so I thought C must be Choco-sen's.
決定権はずっと食べていたいかどうかだった。
The deciding factor was whether I wanted to keep eating it.
お二人ともね牛丼への熱い思いをありがとうございました！
Thank you both for your passionate thoughts on beef bowls!
それでは、正解はこちら！
Well then, the answer is here!
正解 A: 高級牛丼 B: 一般的な牛丼 C: 手作り牛丼
Correct Answer A: High-end Beef Bowl B: General Beef Bowl C: Homemade Beef Bowl
Aは高級牛丼！
A is High-end Beef Bowl!
Bは一般的な牛丼！
B is General Beef Bowl!
そしてCはチョコの牛丼ということで！
And C is Choco's Beef Bowl!
やったー！正解！
We did it! Correct!
牛丼はそれぐらいさ、なんかあれなんですよ。
Beef bowls are like that.
あまり食べたことない人でもなんか味が分かりやすくね、もうとにかく一般食ですね。
Even for people who haven't eaten them much, the taste is easy to understand, they're just a common food.
そう、いや、普通に日本の、まあ文化的な...
Yeah, well, normally Japan's, well, cultural...
あ、ちょっと良いこと言いたいんですけど、全然語彙力が無いんですけど。
Ah, I want to say something good, but I have no vocabulary at all.
まあ牛丼はとにかくね日常食なんで。
Well, anyway, beef bowls are a daily meal.
はい！もう完璧です。イエイ！
Yes! Perfect. Yay!
いやでもこれなら毎日食べれると思う。
No but I think I could eat this every day.
確かに！牛丼本当に毎日食べれる。ガチガチ。
True! I could really eat beef bowls every day. For real, for real.
え、嬉しい！
Oh, I'm happy!
牛丼団長様毎...毎晩さ、こ...毎食か、毎食食べれるっての分かったでしょう？味全然違うんですよ。
Gyudon Captain-sama... every night... every meal, every meal, you saw I can eat it, right? The tastes are completely different.
全然違う！
Completely different!
これを見て挑戦したいと思ったホロメンは居るのかどうか。
I wonder if there are any Holo-members who want to take on this challenge after seeing this.
我こそはという方はね、是非挑戦してみてください。
Those who think they have what it takes, please give it a try.
以上、第1回ホロライブ牛丼女王決定戦でした！
That concludes the 1st Hololive Beef Bowl Queen Finals!
イエイ！めっちゃ美味しかった！
Yay! It was so delicious!
ちなみにみんな忘れてるかもしれないけど、これ生誕祭のライブです。
By the way, everyone might have forgotten, but this is a birthday live.
このあとライブパートなんで、はい、いっぱい食べたんでいっぱい歌って踊ります！
The live performance part starts now, so, yes, I've eaten a lot so I'll sing and dance a lot!
背は高いほうがいいけど
I'd prefer someone tall
そんなタイプじゃなかったの
But you weren't that type
気難しい感じどっちかっていうと苦手だったかな
I guess I was a bit bad with the difficult types
話すと全然違ってて
But when we talk, it's totally different
笑うと目が子供みたいで
When you laugh, your eyes are like a child's
クシャクシャになっちゃう目元なんかにすごいドキってしたりして
And I get really excited by the way your eyes crinkle up
でもなんで本当のこと言っちゃうバカなの
But why do you say the truth, you're such a fool
最初は彼女いないって嘘つくのが礼儀でしょ普通
Usually it's common courtesy to lie at first and say you don't have a girlfriend
そうよなんでこんな振られた気分なの
That's right, why do I feel like I've been dumped
夢見る前から叶わない恋って気づいちゃったじゃない
I've realized it's a love that won't come true even before I can dream
大好きになったどうしようまだ出会ったばかりなんだけど
I've fallen in love, what should I do? We've only just met
切ない気持ちがあふれてきて胸がキュンってなってるよ
Painful feelings are overflowing and my heart is throbbing
そうよ大好きなんだどうにもこうにもすごいことになってきたよ
That's right, I love you, things have gotten really serious
...たい気持ちで頭の中
...with these feelings, my head is...
ふわふわってなってるよ
...becoming fluffy.
手をつないで
Hold my hand.
離さないで
Don't let go.
見つめ合って
Stare into each other's eyes.
抱きしめ合って
Embrace each other.
キスし合って
Kiss each other.
髪を触って
Touch my hair.
いつまでもずっとこうしてて
Let's stay like this forever.
甘いものが好きで盛り上がって
We got excited over liking sweet things,
食べに行こうよなんてなって
And we talked about going out to eat.
ランチならまあいいかって
I thought, "Lunch should be fine,"
なんかありがちな感じよね
It's such a common feeling, isn't it?
ビュッフェの列に並んでたの
We were standing in the buffet line,
普通に話してるんだけど
Just talking normally,
顔近すぎだってまたなんか
But our faces were too close, and once again,
意味なくドキッとしたりして
My heart skipped a beat for no reason.
ピアスこれいいねって褒められて
You complimented my earrings, saying they looked good,
舞い上がったけど彼女にも
And I was over the moon, but then you said,
見せてあげようって写メ撮られるって
"Let me show them to her," and you took a photo.
これどうなの?
What's the deal with that?
そう、よなんでこんな惨めな気分なの
Right, why do I feel so miserable like this?
戦うことすらできないバリア
A barrier I can't even fight against
張られちゃって、No!
has been put up. No!
大好きになった同士
Even though we've just become
見つめあったばかりなんなんだけど
people who love each other and stare at each other,
悲しい気持ちが溢れてきて
Sad feelings are overflowing,
胸がキュンってなってるよ
And my chest feels tight.
そうよ、大好きなんだなんだかんだ
That's right, I love you, somehow or another.
止まらなくなっちゃったかも
I might not be able to stop.
行けない、気持ちで体中
With these hopeless feelings, my whole body
ふわふわってなってるよ
is becoming fluffy.
手をつないで
Hold my hand.
離さないで
Don't let go.
見つめ合って
Stare into each other's eyes.
抱きしめ合って
Embrace each other.
キスし合って
Kiss each other.
髪を触って
Touch my hair.
いつまでもずっとこうしてて
Let's stay like this forever.
もしも願いが叶うなら
If my wish could come true,
出会いの日リセットボタンを押させて
Let me press the reset button on the day we met.
そうよ、神様この馬鹿な鐘が
That's right, God, before this stupid bell
恋なんてする前のピュアな心に
begins to ring, to my pure heart before falling in love,
私を連れてって下さい
please take me back there.
ゴールデンタイムラバー / 作詞・作曲：スキマスイッチ
Golden Time Lover / Lyrics & Composition: Sukima Switch
集中できていないな まだ体が迷っているんだ
I can't seem to concentrate, my body is still hesitating.
震えていたんじゃ コントロールしたってブレるんだ
If I'm trembling, even if I'm in control, I'll still waver.
太陽も月もなんも 完全にこっち向いていないが
Neither the sun nor the moon are turned this way at all.
やるしかないんだと 言い聞かせるようにそうつぶやいた
Telling myself I have no choice, I whispered it as if to convince myself.
状況は悪いが ただ逃げ出すんじゃ根性ないな
The situation is bad, but just running away shows no guts.
展望はないが 度胸でクリアするしかないや
There's no outlook, but I've got no choice but to clear it with nerve.
衝動は抑えたまま ターゲットとの間隔探れ
With my impulses suppressed, I'll gauge the distance from the target.
必要なもんは 勝つプライド
What I need is the pride to win.
味わうのは勝利の美酒か それとも敗北の苦汁か
Shall I taste the sweet wine of victory, or the bitter dregs of defeat?
そう すべては2つに1つ
Right, it's always one of two choices.
操りたい運命の糸を
I want to manipulate the threads of fate.
絶好のゴールデンタイム
The perfect golden time,
この手で掴め
Seize it with these hands.
渾身のポーカーフェイス
My best poker face,
キメて仕掛けるよ
I'll set it and make my move.
イリュージョンの世界へ引き込んで
Into a world of illusion, dragging you in.
引き込んで
Dragging you in...
際限ないプレッシャーゲーム
A limitless pressure game,
スルリと抜けて
Slip right through it.
栄光のボーダーライン
The border line of glory,
飛び越えるために
In order to leap over it.
ハウメニー?
How many?
どれくらいの代償いる?
How much of a price is required?
手放したくないもんはどれ？
Which of these things do I not want to let go of?
論より証拠なんだ 要は結果を出したもんが勝者だ
Proof is better than theory. In short, the one who delivers results is the winner.
沈黙は金だ 口が過ぎればバレるんだ
Silence is golden. If you talk too much, you'll be found out.
感覚を研ぎ澄まして 慎重に流れを読み切れ
Sharpen your senses and read the flow carefully.
現状の勝率 何パーセント？
What's the current win rate percentage?
勝ち割るのは堅実なゲームセンス
What breaks through to victory is a solid game sense.
潜む影法師は悪魔か？
Is the lurking silhouette a devil?
男ならば 潔く散ってやるくらいの覚悟で挑め
If you're a man, take on the challenge with the resolve to go out in a blaze of glory.
逆境のクラップユアハンズ 奮い立たせて
Clap your hands in adversity and rouse yourself.
斬新なファイティングスタイル ギリギリを攻めろ
A novel fighting style, attack right on the edge.
アテンション 危ないぜ 限界超えて
Attention, it's dangerous, go beyond your limits.
最高のフェアリーテイル 歴史に刻め
Etch the greatest fairy tale into history.
完勝の瞬間を 見せつけるために
In order to show off the moment of complete victory.
アーユーレディ？ くぐもった迷いなど捨て
Are you ready? Throw away your muffled doubts.
バベルの階段をあがれ
And climb the stairs of Babel.
女神のように微笑を浮かべる
Wearing a goddess-like smile,
君の魅力に取っ捕まって
I'm trapped by your charm,
誘われるまま 堕ちていく
Falling down just as I'm invited.
心に住みついた欲望
The desire that's taken root in my heart,
膨れあがる 果てなき夢
An endless, swelling dream.
誰も僕を とめられない
No one can stop me.
絶好のゴールデンタイム この手で掴め
Seize the perfect golden time with these hands.
渾身のポーカーフェイス キメて仕掛けるよ
Put on your best poker face and make your move.
イリュージョンの世界へ 引きずり込んで
Dragging you into a world of illusion.
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム スルリと抜けて
Slipping through the endless pressure game,
栄光のボーダーライン 飛び越えるために
To leap over the border line of glory.
ハウメニー？ どれくらいの代償がいる？
How many? What kind of price is required?
逆境のクラップユアハンズ 奮い立たせて
Clap your hands in adversity and rouse yourself.
斬新なファイティングスタイル ギリギリを攻めろ
A novel fighting style, attack right on the edge.
アテンション 危ないぜ 限界超えて
Attention, it's dangerous, go beyond your limits.
最高のフェアリーテイル 歴史に刻め
Etch the greatest fairy tale into history.
驚愕の大逆転 華麗に決めるよ
I'll pull off a stunning comeback with style.
ドゥーユーノウ？ 運命は奪い取るもの
Do you know? Fate is something you seize for yourself.
バベルの頂上に差す 太陽の光を浴びろ
Bask in the sunlight that hits the top of Babel.
ノエルー！ ぺこらー！ クロヱー！ お誕生日おめでとうー！
Noel! Pekora! Chloe! Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
嬉しいなー！ 豪華！
I'm so happy! This is so grand!
てか何この3人... シナジーなくね？
Wait, what's with this trio? There's no synergy here, is there?
言っちゃった... まず、最初にクロちゃんこのステージをお貸ししまして、ありがとう
She said it... First off, Chloe-chan, thank you for letting us use this stage.
あ、どうぞどうぞ！ こちらこそ！ 嬉しい！
Ah, please, feel free! Same here! I'm happy!
いや、みんな分かったよね？ ちょっとリスナーさん、コメントちょっとね
Well, everyone figured it out, right? Listeners, check the comments.
え、分かった？ 分かった？ 分かった？
Eh, did you get it? Did you? Did you?
はい、正解がいっぱいいますので、言うと...
Yes, there are many correct answers, so let's say it...
おっ？
Oh?
我ら、スロカス三姉妹！
We are the Slot-Scum Sisters!
ちょっ、ちょっと待って！ 不本意な感じのふわっとした紹介！
Wait, wait a minute! That's such an unwilling, vague introduction!
そうだよ、クロちゃん、ぺこら、私違うよ！
That's right, Chloe-chan, Pekora... I'm different!
違います！ アイドル！ アイドルでしょ！
We're different! We're idols! Idols, right?!
スロットしてたじゃない！ さっきまで！
You were playing slots! Until just now!
お前だけだよ！
That was only you!
スロカス！ お前も！ ぺこらも！
Slot addicts! You too! And Pekora too!
だってさ、だからギャンブル好きだからさ、色々...
Well, because we like gambling, various things...
アンケートとかももらったりしてさ。
We even got responses to a survey and stuff.
ほら、ね？
See, right?
そうだよね。
That's right.
トゥー！
Tooh!
あら！
Oh!
はっ！
Hah!
チュン！ズンスン！ズンスン！
Chun! Zun-zun! Zun-zun!
ほら、手が覚えてる！
Look, my hands remember!
勝手に体が！あぁ、止まらない！
My body's doing it on its own! Ah, it won't stop!
止まらないでしょ！
It won't stop, right?!
ちょっと、クロエちゃん、今からうちに行くか！
Wait, Chloe-chan, want to come to my place now?!
行きますか！
Shall we?!
行くかぁ！
Let's go!
じゃあな！お疲れ様でーす！
See ya! Good job everyone!
団長もうち行きたいけど、
I want to go too, but...
誕生日、まだまだあるよ！
The birthday celebration is still going on!
ん〜〜っ！
Mmm~~!
シャシャシャシャシャシャシャシャ... エブリバディ！
Sha sha sha sha... Everybody!
シャシャシャシャシャシャシャ... エブリバディ！
あつまれ！パーティーピーポー
Gather up, party people!
朝までダンス
Dance until morning.
酒があったら情報開示してウェーホウ
If there's alcohol, disclose information and way-ho!
暗闇でサングラス
Sunglasses in the dark.
社交の低さをステータス
Making low social skills a status.
流しているEDM
EDM is playing.
Dancing to the EDM
あつまれ！パーティーピーポー
Gather up, party people!
朝までダンス
Dance until morning.
酒があったら情報開示してウェーホウ
If there's alcohol, disclose information and way-ho!
ショートカットでツーブロックの
Girls with a short cut and undercut,
女は大体ダンス上手い
Are usually good at dancing.
パリピ 俺も混ぜてくれ
Party people, let me join in too.
酒飲め 飯踊れ 偏見同士
Drink up, eat, dance, bunch of prejudiced folks.
パリピ パリピ 平日はちゃんと働いてる
Party people, party people, working hard on weekdays.
パリピ 偉い
Party people, you're great.
パリピ パリピ 混ぜてくれ
Party people, party people, let me join in.
酒飲め 飯踊れ 偏見同士
Drink up, eat, dance, bunch of prejudiced folks.
パリピ パリピ 休日、日サロで焼いてる
Party people, party people, tanning at the salon on weekends.
パリピ 偉い
Party people, you're great.
レッドブルで割った酒飲んで
Drinking alcohol mixed with Red Bull,
吐いた女持ち帰って
Taking home the girl who puked,
朝まで楽しむ パーティーピーポー
Party people enjoying themselves until morning.
イェーイ！
Yay!
いっぱい飲んだ！
I drank a lot!
飲んだねー！
We sure did!
いっぱい飲んだ。
Drank a lot.
いや、今日はお祝い事ですからね！
Well, it's a celebration today!
おめでとうー！ハッピーバースデー！
Congratulations! Happy Birthday!
ハッピーバースデー！ハッピーバースデー！
Happy Birthday! Happy Birthday!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
酒！酒！酒！
Sake! Sake! Sake!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
パリピしたねー！
We partied hard!
パリピしたいや。
I want to party more.
でもさ、お祝い事と言えばさ、
But speaking of celebrations...
ほら！
Look!
ここにホロ酒飲み組にいますよ！新メンバー！
The Holo-Sake-Drinking Group is right here! New members!
新メンバー加入おめでとう！酒を浴びろー！
Congrats on joining! Bathe in alcohol!
イェーイ！おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
新メンバー加入だ！やったー！
A new member has joined! Yay!
ホロでもね、酒飲みがいましたけど、
In Hololive, we had some drinkers already, but...
より強固な酒飲みが来ちゃって。
Now an even more hardcore drinker has arrived.
そうだね。
That's right.
よろしくお願いします。
Looking forward to it.
ワイン担当だから。
I'm the wine specialist.
ワイン担当。
Wine specialist.
そう、今日はちょっとね... 日本酒だけど。
Yeah, today we have... Japanese sake, though.
よく振ってたよ、これ。
You were shaking this a lot.
振っちゃいけない。良い子は振っちゃいけないからね。
Don't shake it. Good kids shouldn't shake it, okay?
真似しちゃダメですよ。真似しないでくださいね。
Don't imitate us. Please don't imitate us.
いやー。なんかある？他。
Yeah... Anything else?
やめてくださいよ～
Please stop it!
誕生日だからそんなこと言わないで！
It's my birthday, so don't say that!
あっち向いて、みんな写真撮ろう！
Turn that way, let's take a photo everyone!
行くよ？
Ready?
せーの！カンパーイ！イェーイ！
One, two! Cheers! Yay!
ああ、満足だ。これスクショ。
Ah, I'm satisfied. This is the screenshot.
あれ、ハッシュタグでね、いっぱいスクショしてください。
Please post lots of screenshots with the hashtag.
ほら、ホロ酒飲み組と。
Look, with the Holo-drinking group.
あと、今日のハッシュタグは？
And what's today's hashtag?
今日のハッシュタグは、ここに書いてあります。
Today's hashtag is written right here.
でーす！よろしくお願いしまーす！
It is! Please support us!
あと美味しいお酒いっぱい飲んでください！
Also, please drink lots of delicious alcohol!
はーい！飲んじゃってくださーい！
Okay! Please drink up!
ノエルデポーションもよろしくね！
Check out the Noel Potion too!
いや、この後の曲いきましょうか。
Well, shall we go to the next song?
そうだね！ありあり！
That's right! Definitely!
あ、団長まだある。
Ah, Danchou still has more.
あ、じゃあ頑張って！
Oh, then good luck!
いやいやいや、
No, no, no,
じゃあ4人で、最後みんなで！
let's do it with the four of us, everyone together!
シャシャシャシャシャシャシャシャシャシャシャシャン！
Sha-sha-sha-sha-sha-sha-sha-sha-sha-sha-sha-shan!
リン・ドン リン・ドン コンドアガビビッ / キタイもヒタップ カンジテ
Ding-dong, ding-dong, next I'll be surprised / Feel the expectations filling up
リリカルMonster / 作詞：モリタコータ / 作曲：清水武亜(HANO)・日山夕次(HANO)・廣澤優也(HANO)
Lyrical Monster / Lyrics: Kota Morita / Composition: Takea Shimizu, Yuji Hiyama, Yuya Hirosawa
ジョイ・ジョイ モット・エンジョイ / リリカル・スウィーミング
Joy, joy, more enjoy / Lyrical swimming
ジョー・ジョー キブンモ ツヨツヨ ホームラン
Up, up, feeling stronger and stronger, home run
ダンチョウ シンノ サイノウ ヒエラルキー
Danchou's true talent, the hierarchy
ミセテアゲル ラブリー・パーティ
I'll show you, lovely party
ズルズル ピルズル マキオコス コトノハ タイフーン
Drag, drag, pill-drag, causing a typhoon of words
モット・ハッピー トコトンドコトン トドケチャウヨ
More happy, delivering it all the way
ソウダロウ コンナロウ トキメキ・タロウ / ララライフ イッツ・パワー・デスカ？
That's right, such a guy, heartbeat Taro / La-la-life, is it power?
チョット・ウェイウェイ ト カンジタラ
When you feel a little "way-way"
トメラレナイ トメタクナイクライ ムネノ ドキ・ドキ ドキ！
I can't stop, I don't want to stop, the thumping in my chest!
イッシュウ マワッテ ゲンザイ シンコウ
Going around once, currently in progress
グルグル オイカケッコ アラララ アラ モード！
Round and round, chasing each other, oh-la-la-la, a la mode!
コノママ イクヨ
Here we go like this
リン・ドン リン・ドン コンドアガビビッ / キタイもヒタップ モット カンジテ
Ding-dong, ding-dong, next I'll be surprised / Feel the expectations filling up even more
ジャンピン・ジャンピン ディスプレー オジャミ
Jumping, jumping, display, beanbag
オウ・サバイバル・シンセダイ
Oh, survival new generation
イロハ・ハロー ワ ミトメマセン
Iroha Hello, I won't admit it
シジョウ サイコウ ノ コトダマ イッサ
The best spirit of words in history, ever
ユー・アー・アイ ココカラ レディ
You are I, ready from here
ズット ミテテ リリカル・モンスター
Always keep watching, Lyrical Monster
Merry-go-round / Candy-go-round / Ready-go-round / ユメノ ヨウナ スピード デ エスコート
Merry-go-round / Candy-go-round / Ready-go-round / Escorting you at a speed like a dream
Candy-Go-Round / 作詞：高瀬愛虹 / 作曲：Devin Kinoshita
Candy-Go-Round / Lyrics: Aiko Takase / Composition: Devin Kinoshita
トキ ノ ナガレ ワ イツデモ ユックリ
The flow of time is always slow
ダケド ハート ノ ウゴク スピード ヒラグレバ
But if the speed of the heart's movement flutters
キカセテ ヨ コノ バショ エ
Let me hear it, to this place
チャント トドク ヨウ ニ
So that it reaches properly
キミニ クラップ クラップ クラップ
Clap clap clap for you
エディバリ クラップ ハンズ アップ / フサレタ ナラ
Everybody clap hands up / If it's closed
Merry-go-round / Candy-go-round / Ready-go-round / ユメノ ヨウナ スピード デ トビタトウ
Merry-go-round / Candy-go-round / Ready-go-round / Let's fly away at a speed like a dream
ウサギ ニ ノリコメバ イケルン ダ / タイムスリップ モウ トメラレナイ
If you jump onto the rabbit, you can go / Time slip, can't be stopped anymore
Merry-go-round / Candy-go-round
ハジマリ ノ ベル ガ ナリヒビク ヨル ニ
In the night where the bell of the beginning rings
ムカエ ニ イクカラ
Because I'm going to pick you up
オナジ リズム デ ジョイフル ナ ナンバー カナデヨウ
Let's play a joyful number with the same rhythm
カンヅイテイル デショ ココ ニ イル イミ サエ モ
I'm sure you've noticed the very meaning of being here
Suspect / 作詞・作曲：Kyota.
Suspect / Lyrics & Composition: Kyota.
キリフダ ワ ソレゾレ タガイ ノ テフダ ニ
The trump cards are in each other's hands
アタマ ト ココロ デ アバキダシテ ムネ オ ウチヌケ
Unmask it with your head and heart, pierce the chest
ジカク ナイ デショ ネ オモイドオリ ニ
You don't realize it, do you? Just as I thought
キミ ワ ウゴカサレテイル コト
That you are being moved
タンジュン ジャナイ ノ カケヒキ ノ ヒント オ
It's not simple, the hints of the bargaining
スベテ ヒロイアゲテ
Pick up everything
フミニ ジョーカー テニスル コト デ
By getting the Joker on the second move
リカイデキタ アイ ノ カタチ オ
The shape of love that you could understand
ドコカ ノ ダレカ ニ シクマレテイテ モ
Even if it's set up by someone somewhere
サイゴ ニ ワラウ キミ ト
With you who laughs in the end
カクシン シテイク / フタリ ノ コドウ / シンリセン ガ ツギ ノ ステージ ヘ
I'm becoming certain / Our heartbeats / The psychological war goes to the next stage
でいり〜だいあり〜！
Daily Diary!
特別すごいことなんてそう起こらないリアル
Reality is that nothing particularly amazing really happens
だけどそのエッセンスがその世界 夢に変えて
But that essence turns that world into a dream
毎日がパラダイス
Every day is a paradise
思い切り遊んで笑っちゃおう
Let's play and laugh to our hearts' content
ノエル！
Noel!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
4回目祝えて嬉しいよ
I'm so happy to celebrate for the fourth time
今年も後わずかになったね
There's only a little bit left of this year, isn't there?
今年も大変お世話になりました
Thank you for all your help this year
来年もよろしく！
I'm looking forward to next year too!
ちょっと待って。年越しムーブなんだけど。
Wait a minute. This is totally a New Year's Eve vibe.
どんな毎日も 楽しくなっちゃうんだ
No matter what kind of day it is, it becomes fun
だっていつだって ほらあなたが待ってるの
Because look, you're always waiting
みんなで毎日を 出会えた嬉しい日を
Together every day, these happy days we met
みんなと一緒に気分はね もう最高潮
When I'm with everyone, I feel like I'm at the peak
窓の向こうの笑顔に手を振って
Waving to the smiles beyond the window
配信で届ける「あわでいり〜だいあり〜」
Delivering our daily diary through streaming
青春実況中
Streaming our youth
挑戦配信中
Broadcasting our challenges
青春実況中
Streaming our youth
挑戦配信中
Broadcasting our challenges
でいり〜だいあり〜 届けよう
Let's deliver our daily diary
ノエル！
Noel!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
あー！ ありがとう！
Ah! Thank you!
4回目祝えて嬉しいよ。
I'm so happy to celebrate for the fourth time.
今年も後わずかになったね。
There's only a little bit left of this year.
今年も大変お世話になりました。
Thank you for everything this year.
来年もよろしく。
Looking forward to next year too.
え、ちょっと待って！
Wait, wait a minute!
え、何？ 何これ？
What? What's this?
いや、それ2回目だし、ちょっと待って！
No, that's the second time, hold on!
はい！ 集合、集合、ピース！
Okay! Gather 'round, gather 'round, peace!
あー、みんな使い回しがバレたから。
Ah, everyone saw through the recycled routine.
2回目だめだよね、ちょっと。
Doing it a second time is a bit much.
しかも、動きおかしくなってたからね。
Besides, the movements were getting weird.
ちょ、おかしいってあなたの動きですけど。
Wait, your movements are the ones that are weird.
自分ってこんな動きしてたんだ。気持ち悪いよ！
I didn't know I moved like that. It's gross!
いやー、でも本当に、みんな来てくれてありがとう！忙しい中。
Anyway, thank you all so much for coming despite your busy schedules!
このメンバー、何で呼ばれたか分かりますか？想像つくかな？
Do you know why I called this group together? Any guesses?
今日ははっぴーライブということで。
Since today is a 'Happy Live'...
本当に一緒に歌いたい、大好きな人を集めたんですけど。
I gathered people I truly love and wanted to sing with.
え、好きってこと！？
What, you love us!?
え、え、え、え、え、え！！！
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!!!
そうなの。しかもメドレーでしたら、すごい面白いかなと思って。
Exactly. And I thought it would be really fun if we did a medley.
楽しかった！
It was fun!
この5人でちょっと写真撮って。結構圧巻じゃないですか？
Let's take a photo with the five of us. It's quite a sight, isn't it?
何か横にでかいハムスターいるよ。
There's a huge hamster next to us.
大納言さん。
That's Dainagon-san.
大納言さんいいの？映らなくて。
Is Dainagon-san okay not being in the shot?
じゃあこっちの大納言と一緒に。
Then let's take it with this Dainagon.
じゃあこっちの前に集まる？
Should we gather in front of this one?
イェーイ！
Yay!
こっちの大納言も寂しがってる。
This Dainagon is lonely too.
はい、チーズ！
Say cheese!
ハムスターじゃないよ。
It's not a hamster.
イェーイ！
Yay!
満足。ありがとうみんな。
That was great. Thank you, everyone.
まだまだライブ続くんで。団長頑張りやす！
The live is still going. Captain Noel will do her best!
頑張ってねー！
Good luck!
皆さん良いお年を！
Happy New Year, everyone!
来年は幸せになれますように。
I hope next year will be a happy one.
いや、今年も幸せなのよ。
No, I'm happy this year too.
今も幸せだからね。
I'm happy right now.
ありがとうございましたー。
Thank you so much.
来年もよろしくねー。
Looking forward to next year too.
頑張る。まだ明けてないよ。
I'll do my best. The year hasn't ended yet.
来年から頑張る。頑張ろう！ イェーイ！
I'll do my best from next year. Let's go! Yay!
消える飛行機雲 僕たちは見送った
We watched as the vapor trails disappeared
眩しくて逃げた
It was so bright that I ran away
Dazzled, I ran away
いつだって弱くて
I was always weak
あの日から変わらず
Unchanged from that day
いつまでも変わらずに
Remaining unchanged forever
いられなかったこと
The fact that I couldn't stay that way
悔しくて指を...
Is frustrating, and I let go of...
...離す
...your fingers.
あの鳥はまだうまく飛べないけど
That bird still can't fly well, but
いつか風を切って知る
One day it will cut through the wind and know
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The unreachable place is still far away
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it, keeping only my wish inside
子供たちは夏の線路 歩く
The children walk along the summer tracks
吹く風に素足をさらして
Exposing their bare feet to the blowing wind
遠くには幼かった日々を
In the distance, those childhood days
両手には飛び立つ希望を
In their hands, the hope to take flight
消える飛行機雲
A fading vapor trail,
追いかけて 追いかけて
chasing it, chasing it
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらず
Unchanged from that day we crossed this hill
いつまでも真っ直ぐに僕らはあるように
Wishing that we could always be straightforward
海神のような強さを守れるよ
We can protect a strength like that of the sea god
きっと
I'm sure of it
あの空を回る風車の羽たちは
The wings of the windmill turning in that sky
いつまでも同じ夢見る
Will dream the same dream forever
届かない場所をずっと見つめてる
I keep gazing at that unreachable place
願いを秘めた鳥の夢を
Dreaming the dream of the bird with a hidden wish
振り返る焼けた線路
Looking back at the scorched tracks
覆う入道雲
and the towering clouds covering them
形を変えても僕らは覚えていて
Even if their shapes change, let's remember
どうか季節が残した昨日を
Please, the yesterday that the season left behind
消える飛行機雲
A fading vapor trail,
追いかけて 追いかけて
chasing it, chasing it
早すぎる合図 僕ら笑い出してる
At a signal that came too soon, we start to laugh
いつまでも真っ直ぐに眼差しはあるように
Wishing that our gaze could always be straightforward
汗が滲んでも手を離さないよ
Even if our hands get sweaty, I won't let go
ずっと
Forever
消える飛行機雲 僕たちは見送った
We watched the vapor trail as it disappeared
眩しくて逃げた
Dazzled, I ran away
いつだって弱くて
I was always weak
あの日から変わらず
Unchanged from that day
いつまでも変わらずに
Remaining unchanged forever
いられなかったこと
The fact that I couldn't stay that way
悔しくて指を...
Is frustrating, and I let go of...
...離す
...your fingers.
はい、鳥の詩でしたー！
Yes, that was Tori no Uta!
いや、すごい。なんか羽ばたいていく感じ。
Wow, that was amazing. I felt like I was flying.
羽ばたく...大空に鳥に...羽ばたく...
Flapping wings... like a bird in the sky... flying...
あ、ちょっと待って。あ、なんか団長、あれが歌いたくなってきちゃったー！
Oh, wait. I suddenly feel like singing *that* song!
ドーン！歌いまーす！
Boom! I'm going to sing!
ギラギラの太陽がある
There's a blazing sun
ワクワクが待ちきれない
I can't wait for the excitement
あれもしたいこれもしたい
I want to do this and that
Let's Summertime!
太陽少女
作詞：Mitsu (TRYTONELABO)
作曲：TAKT (TRYTONELABO)
Taiyou Shoujo
Lyrics: Mitsu (TRYTONELABO)
Composition: TAKT (TRYTONELABO)
青い空と白い雲が
The blue sky and white clouds
心のボルテージあげていく
Pump up the voltage in my heart
ラムネ色のTシャツはね
This ramune-colored T-shirt
今年一番のレコメンド
Is my top recommendation this year
走り出した海岸線
The coastline I started running along
どこまでだって行けそうだね
Seems like I can go anywhere
数え切れない夏休みチャレンジ
Countless summer vacation challenges
君も一緒に行こう！
You come along too!
あっという間に進んでく時計
The clock ticks by in a flash
短すぎじゃない？ My Summertime
Isn't it too short? My Summertime
全部最高のメモリアルにしたい追い風
I want to make it all the best memorial with a tailwind
みんな連れて行け！
Take everyone along!
素晴らしい太陽がサンサン
The wonderful sun is shining brightly
せーのでJUMP！
Ready, JUMP!
はじける汗
Sweat bursting forth
宝石みたいにキラキラ
Sparkling like jewels
眩しく輝け！
Shine brilliantly!
ギラギラの太陽がある
There's a blazing sun
ドキドキがいっぱいです
I'm full of excitement
あれもやろうこれもやろう
Let's do this and that
Let's Summertime!
涼しい風寝転がって
Lying down in the cool breeze
のびのびってお昼寝もいいの
Taking a relaxing nap is nice too
夢の中ならなんだってできちゃう
I can do anything in my dreams
キラキラ光るスーパースター
A sparkling superstar
流れ星を見つけに行こう
Let's go find a shooting star
夜更かしだってへっちゃらだよ
I don't mind staying up late
願い事が溢れそうな時は
When my wishes are about to overflow
Milky WayにDiving!
Diving into the Milky Way!
ちょっとくらい下手だって平気
It's okay if I'm a bit clumsy
みんながくれるファイトがある
I have the spirit everyone gives me
どこまでだって駆け抜けて行けたらいいよね
It would be great if I could run anywhere
準備はOK?
Are you ready?
はぁ、疲れた。もうだめだ...
Whew, I'm tired. I can't do any more...
ちゅわーす！ノエル、応援に来たぞー！
Chuwass! Noel, I've come to cheer you on!
ス、スバル先輩！？でも、もうだめ...
S-Subaru-senpai!? But I'm at my limit...
ほら頑張って！始まるよ！行くよ！
Come on, do your best! It's starting! Let's go!
ひとつひとつが全部全部が
Every single thing
届いてるから上を向いて
Is reaching you, so look up
体中に息を吸い込んだら
Take a deep breath
叫んでみよう
Let's shout it out
みんな大好き！
I love you all!
ノエル、おめでとう！
Congratulations, Noel!
毎日が記念日になーれ
May every day be an anniversary
キミのココロ照らしちゃおう
I'll light up your heart
新しい元気をまるっと
Delivering a whole bunch
お届けしちゃうよ
Of new energy to you
空の彼方まで飛んで行こう
Let's fly to the ends of the sky
せーのでJUMP！
Ready, JUMP!
はじける汗
Sweat bursting forth
宝石みたいにキラキラ
Sparkling like jewels
眩しく輝け！
Shine brilliantly!
ギラギラの太陽がある
There's a blazing sun
欲張っていっちゃいます
I'm going to be greedy
あれもしようこれもしよう
I'll do this and that
Let's Summertime!
わー！ノエルすごーい！おめでとー！
Wow! Noel, you're amazing! Congratulations!
どうしたのノエル？スバル先輩だよ！
What's wrong, Noel? It's me, Subaru-senpai!
えーん...スバル先輩の太陽少女歌えてよかった...
Sob... I'm so glad I could sing your 'Taiyou Shoujo'...
ノエルが主役だろー！
But you're the star here!
ノエル本当に本当におめでとう！ダンスすごかったよ！歌も！
Noel, serious congratulations! Your dance and singing were great!
団長ずっと去年のスバル先輩のライブを見てからどうしても夢があって...
Ever since I saw your live performance last year, I've had a dream...
あの団長、スバル先輩の歌を踊って歌って頑張りたいなって...
I wanted to do my best singing and dancing to your song...
思ってたんです！
I was thinking!
そう！
Yeah!
ありがとう、ノエル嬉しい！ホントめちゃめちゃ良かった！
Thank you, Noel, I'm so happy! It was really, really good!
嬉しい！ありがとうございます。
I'm so happy! Thank you very much.
大丈夫？大丈夫？
Are you okay? Are you okay?
なんかダンスしてるときよりも心拍数が...
Somehow, more than when I was dancing, my heart rate is...
高い！いい、今ね、いいよ。
High! It's good, right now, it's good.
なんでだよ！なんでだよ！おかしいだろ！
Why?! Why?! That's weird!
ダンスの時の方がやばいだろ、絶対に。
It must be worse when you're dancing, for sure.
ちょっとね、これからもね、良かったね、仲良くしてね。
Well, from now on too, I'm glad we could do this, let's keep being good friends.
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
イェーイ！イェーイ！ありがとうございます。
Yay! Yay! Thank you very much.
スバル先輩、写真撮りますか？
Subaru-senpai, shall we take a photo?
あ、撮るか！撮る。何にする？
Oh, shall we! Let's take one. What pose?
団長はやっぱ、スバル先輩と今日、歌って踊って...
I really wanted to, with Subaru-senpai today, sing and dance...
歌って踊って...
Sing and dance...
ちょっと好きな振り付けがあって。やっぱ、あれなんですよ、ここ！
There's a choreography I like. It's that one, here!
あ、これね！これ！
Oh, this one! This!
好きだから。あ、ほら、みんな、団長歌って。
Because I like it. Oh, look, everyone, sing with me.
ほら、一緒に、歌って踊ったんだ。
Look, we sang and danced together.
ノエル、おめでとう！
Noel, congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
なんか距離が空いてたらあれじゃん。
If there's distance between us, it's a bit...
そうだね。
You're right.
いや、ハッピーです。今日あれ、ハッピーライブなんで。
No, I'm happy. Because today is the Happy Live.
そうだね、ハッピーって書いてあるからね。
That's true, it says "Happy" on it.
いや、まだまだ実は、ハッピーなことがあってですね。
Actually, there are still more happy things to come.
そうなの？
Really?
そうなんです。ちょっと団長もその準備があるので、一緒に行きますか？
Yes. I also have some preparations to do, so shall we go together?
あ、一緒に。ハッピーしに行こう！
Oh, together. Let's go be happy!
一緒に！
Together!
楽しかったー！いや、めちゃめちゃハッピーなライブだったんじゃないでしょうか。
That was fun! Well, wasn't that a super happy live performance?
いや、最後、いや最後マジで心臓が止まるかと思ったんですけど。
Wow, the end, at the end I really thought my heart was going to stop.
いや、完全にね、団長得なライブでしたけど。
Well, it was a live performance that was entirely to my benefit, but...
いや、これはね、団長が誕生日だからハッピーに過ごそうっていうね、だけじゃないんです！
Well, this isn't just about me having a happy birthday!
えー、ちょっと画面のみんなびっくりしてると思うんですけど。ホントね、なんでハッピーだったか、ちょっと今、言います！
Uh, I think everyone watching is surprised. Really, I'm going to tell you why it was so happy right now!
ドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥル... ドン！なんとこの後、団長、オリ曲出します！イェーイ！
Drumroll... Bam! Believe it or not, after this, I'm releasing an original song! Yay!
そしてお披露目もしちゃいます！ということでね、あの、そのオリ曲のタイトルが「はっぴー」ということで、ひらがなでね、「はっぴー」なんですよ。
And I'll even be performing it for the first time! So, the title of that original song is "Happi", written in hiragana as "はっぴー".
で、しかもその曲を作ってくださった方が、あの有名なDECO*27さんということでね、団長もとうとうDECO*27さんに作ってもらえるようになりました。
And what's more, the person who created this song is the famous DECO*27-san, so I've finally had a song made for me by DECO*27-san.
それはね、皆さんの日々の応援のおかげです。ありがとうございます。
That's all thanks to everyone's daily support. Thank you very much.
ということで、一応、お披露目した後に、あの24時から、あのリリースもされますので、そちらもよろしくお願いします。
So, after the first performance, it will be released at midnight, so please look forward to that as well.
あとね、あの定番なんですが、生誕グッズも発売いたします。それはね、オリ曲の後に発表しますので、何卒よろしくお願いします。
Also, as is standard, birthday goods will also go on sale. I'll announce those after the original song, so please stay tuned for that.
いやー、どんなグッズなんだろうなー、ドンが来るのかな？いやー楽しみなんですけど、最後まで見ててくれると嬉しいです。
Man, I wonder what kind of goods they are... maybe Don will show up? I'm looking forward to it, and I'd be happy if you watched until the end.
そんな、あ、ちなみに生誕グッズはね数量限定なので、はい、あの欲しい人は、あの直筆、あ、生誕グッズ、数量限定じゃない、あ、あ...
By the way, the birthday goods are limited in quantity, so, yes, for those who want them, the handwritten... oh, the birthday goods themselves aren't limited in quantity, ah, uh...
あの数量限定じゃないよ。直筆が数量限定なので、何卒直筆サインが欲しい人は、あの張り付いてね、頑張ってください。
They aren't limited in quantity. It's the handwritten signatures that are limited, so those who really want a handwritten signature, please stay glued to your screens and do your best.
そしてね、メンバー限定に、あのグリーンバック素材とかもあります。このね、アイドル衣装だったりとかのグリーンバック素材もあるので。
And also, for members only, there will be green screen assets and such. There will be green screen assets of this idol outfit and more.
そちらも要チェック、メンバーさんよろしくね。ということで、あ、時間ない、着替えてきます！
Make sure to check those out too, members. So, oh, I'm out of time, I'm going to change clothes!
オヨヨヨヨヨヨヤ！
Oyoyoyoyoyoyoya!
もうハイになっちゃうよね オッケー
I'm already getting high, right? Okay!
受け取っておね オッケー
Please receive it, okay!
きみのことがだも（ん）好きだもん
Because I love you.
きみのことがだもん / 好き
はっぴー
Happi
作詞・作曲：DECO*27 編曲：Rockwell
Lyrics/Composition: DECO*27, Arrangement: Rockwell
いい感じって
"Feeling good," you say,
勘違いしちゃって
But I misunderstood it,
恥ずかしくなっちゃうじゃん
And now I'm getting embarrassed,
ばかばか
Stupid, stupid!
あ待ってそれ以上わたしに近付かないで
Oh, wait, don't come any closer to me than that!
コーションコーション
Caution, caution!
押し込んだ感情が 脱走脱走
The emotions I've pushed down are escaping, escaping!
脱走
Escape
想いのドミノ 倒してみて
Try knocking over the dominoes of my feelings,
止まらなくて困るかも
They might not stop, and that could be trouble.
言いたいこと全部言えちゃう魔法
A magic spell that lets me say everything I want to say,
とろけちゃうぐらいの鼓動を
A heartbeat so strong it makes me melt,
たっぷりかけて
Pour it on thick!
それで はっぴーじゃん きみが笑うなら
Then it's happy, right? If you're laughing,
それが はっぴーじゃん 心スキップして
That's what's happy! My heart's skipping a beat,
ジャンプして
Jumping around,
落ち込んでだめだめだって
Even when I'm feeling down and useless,
一回のきみの笑顔で
With just one look at your smile,
全部忘れちゃうから
I'll forget it all!
もう何をやったってはいオッケー
No matter what I do, yeah, okay!
謝ったらはいオッケー
If I apologize, yeah, okay!
甘え過ぎたらめってしといてね
If I get too clingy, please tell me "no," okay?
もうハイになっちゃうよね オッケー
I'm already getting high, right? Okay!
受け取っておね オッケー
Please receive it, okay!
きみのことがだも（ん）好きだもん
Because I love you.
きみのことがだもん / 好き
伝えたい言葉が
Words I want to tell you...
溢れ出す気持ちが
Overflowing feelings...
君を目指して
Heading towards you,
また大渋滞して
they're in a huge congestion again.
鳴り響くクラクション
The sounding horn.
思い切っちゃえば楽勝？
Is it an easy victory if I just go for it?
踏んでしまうのは いつもブレーキなんだよ
But what I always step on is the brake.
想いのオセロ 返してみて
Try flipping over the Othello pieces of my feelings.
挟まれたら 染まるかも
If they're sandwiched, they might change color.
言いたいこと全部言えちゃう魔法で
With magic that lets me say everything I want to say,
とろけちゃうくらいの砂糖で
and enough sugar to make me melt,
ドキドキさせたい
I want to make your heart race.
でもあはっぴーじゃん 見てくれなくちゃ
But I'm happy, you have to look at me.
またあはっぴーじゃん 心フリックしてショートして
Happy again, my heart is flicking and shorting out.
落ち込んでだめだめだって 1回の君の笑顔で
Even if I'm down and say it's no good, with just one of your smiles,
全部忘れちゃうけど
I forget everything, but...
それもはっぴーじゃん 君といられたら
That's happy too, if I can be with you.
つまりはっぴーじゃん 心スキップしてジャンプして
In other words, I'm happy, my heart is skipping and jumping.
落ち込んでだめだめだって 1回の君の笑顔で
Even if I'm down and say it's no good, with just one of your smiles,
全部忘れちゃうから
because I'll forget everything.
もう何をやったって はいオッケー！
No matter what I do now, it's okay!
謝ったら はいオッケー！
If I apologize, it's okay!
甘えすぎたら めっ！しといてね
If I'm too spoiled, please scold me!
もうハイになっちゃえ はいオッケー！
Just get high now, it's okay!
受け取ってよね はいオッケー！
Please accept it, okay!
君のことが 好きなんだよ
I really like you!
もう何があったって はいオッケー！
No matter what happens, it's okay!
泣いちゃっても はいオッケー！
Even if I cry, it's okay!
大好きのパフ きっと続いていく
The puff of love will surely continue.
もうハイになっちゃう はいオッケー！
I'm going to get high now, it's okay!
受け取ってよね はいオッケー！
Please accept it, okay!
君のことが 好きすぎ 好きすぎ 好きすぎて
I like you way too much, too much, too much,
私 はっぴーだもん
Because I'm so happy!
第3弾！まだまだお知らせがあります！
Part 3! There's still more news!
今年もノエちゃん誕生日記念グッズ 発売いたしまーす！
This year too, Noel-chan's birthday merchandise will be released!
イエーイ！パフパフパフ！
Yay! *horn sounds*
ということで時間がないのでね、さっと紹介なんですが、
So, since we don't have much time, here's a quick introduction.
今年はね、4種類のグッズを出します。
This year, we're releasing four types of goods.
まず1つ目がバスタオル。
The first one is a bath towel.
これはノエちゃん、なんかちょっとドキッな感じなんですけど、
This one of Noel-chan is a bit heart-pounding,
まあバスタオル姿でね、団員さんの分の牛丼を作って、
but she's in a bath towel, making beef bowls for the members,
お帰りの際をしてる、とっても不思議なバスタオルになっております。
and greeting them home. It's a very mysterious bath towel.
そして、2つ目が白銀愛好会どんぶり2022年バージョンということで、
And the second one is the Shirogane Fan Club Bowl 2022 Version.
以前ね、どんぶり出したことあるんですけど、
We've released a bowl before,
こちらはより、あの、白銀ノエルのオリジナルデザインに近い牛丼のどんぶりとなっております。
but this one is a beef bowl closer to Shirogane Noel's original design.
あの底にね、なんかメッセージがあるみたいなので、お楽しみにということでね。
There seems to be a message at the bottom, so please look forward to that.
で、3つ目が団員手帳です。
The third one is the Member's Notebook.
ま、団員さん、白銀聖騎士団専用の団員手帳となっているので、ぜひぜひここにメモいっぱい書いてください。
It's exclusively for the Shirogane Order of Knights, so please write lots of notes in here.
で、4つ目、最後が団長とお揃いジョッキ。
The fourth and last one is a mug just like the captain's.
これはね、リアンドロ衣装の時のジョッキとなっております。
This is the mug from the time of the Liandlo costume.
お揃っちなんで、ぜひぜひこれでね、お酒を飲んでください。
It's matching, so please use it to drink alcohol.
で、フルセットの特典なんですけど、
As for the full set bonus,
ポストカード、白銀ノエルのメッセージが書いていますので、
it's a postcard with a message from Shirogane Noel.
ぜひぜひ数量限定バージョンはね、あの直筆サインがありますので、なにとぞよろしくお願いします。
The limited edition has her handwritten signature, so please check it out.
特典ASMRボイスはね、あの数量限定、限定じゃない、どちらにもあるので、よろしくお願いします。
The bonus ASMR voice is in both versions, so please look forward to it.
はい、時間がオーバーしました。では、バイバイ！
Okay, I'm out of time. So, bye-bye!
みんな買ってね！団長もっともっとはっぴーになっちゃいます、みんなが買ってくれると。ぜひぜひ買ってください。バイバイ！
Everyone, please buy them! I'll be even happier if you do. Please do buy them. Bye-bye!